Guide to the George Rosen Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- American Public Health Association Files, 1916-1978; Series II
  - American Journal of Public Health
    - Correspondence
      - American Public Health Association, 1971-1974 (Box 15, Folder 9-10)
      - Curran, William J., 1968-1970, undated (Box 16, Folder 11)
      - Everybody's Press, 1971-1973 (Box 16, Folder 12)
      - Lilienfield, Abraham M., 1969-1971 (Box 16, Folder 13)
      - Winslow, Charles-Edward Amory
        See: Series I, folder 345
      - Wright, Nicholas H., 1972-1973 (Box 16, Folder 14)
      - Wylie, Murray, 1971-1972 (Box 16, Folder 15)
      - Yankauer, Alfred, 1971-1977 (Box 16, Folder 16-17)
    - Editorial board
      - General, 1948-1953, 1968-1972, undated (Box 16, Folder 18-23)
      - Minutes and reports, 1955-1970 (Box 17, Folder 24-26)
    - Manuscripts
      - Contributed from annual meeting, 1970-1971 (Box 17, Folder 27-32)
      - Contributed from annual meeting, 1970-1971 (Box 18, Folder 33-34)
      - Rejections, 1969-1971 (Box 18, Folder 35-41)
      - Rejections, 1969-1971 (Box 19, Folder 42-51)
      - Miscellaneous, 1970-1971 (Box 20, Folder 52-54)
    - Retirement of George Rosen, 1973-1974 (Box 20, Folder 55)
    - Russian review papers, 1958 (Box 20, Folder 56)
    - Supplements, 1969-1970, undated (Box 20, Folder 57)
  - Annual meetings, 1950, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 58-59)
  - Centennial committee, 1941-1971, undated (Box 20, Folder 60-61)
  - Committee on anthrax, 1939 (Box 20, Folder 62)
  - Conference on social science and health, 1975-1977, undated (Box 20, Folder 63)
  - Correspondence, 1946-1951, 1968-1978, undated (Box 21, Folder 64-66)
  - Membership, 1918, 1966 (Box 21, Folder 67)
  - Pamphlets, 1926-1934 (Box 21, Folder 68-69)
  - Photographs
    See: Series VI, folders 13-25
  - Social Science and Medicine, 1967-1968 (Box 21, Folder 70)
  - Statistics section, 1916, 1929-1953, 1967- circa 1972 (Box 21, Folder 71-77)
- Subject Files, Series III
  Arranged alphabetically, Subject Files consist of materials documenting organizations, individuals, publications, and topics of interest to Rosen. The files documenting the publication Ciba Symposia comprise the most substantial section of the series. George Rosen and his wife, Beate Caspari-Rosen, shared editorial duties for the journal and each of their tenures is documented separately. Adhering to the original order of the materials, the George Rosen files are arranged chronologically, while the Beate Caspari-Rosen files are arranged alphabetically.
  The series also includes folders documenting other publications, most notably Journal of the History of Medicine and Allied Sciences, which Rosen helped incorporate in 1946 and edited until 1952. Correspondence in Series I with Henry Schuman and Madeline Stanton also includes documentation of this journal.
  The National Institute of Health represents the most significant of the many organizations documented in the series. The materials document Rosen's work on an oral history grant project on the history of health research in the United States and include correspondence, reports, proposals, and outlines. Transcripts of the project reside in the National Library of Medicine.
  Files on a number of individuals such as Michael Alexis, Francis Blake, Harvey Cushing, Haven Emerson, Joseph Mountin, Milton Rosenau, A. M. Stimson, Edward Streeter and Charles-Edward Amory Winslow contain collected information and reflect Rosen's research interests. The same is true of the topical files covering cancer, dance frenzy, infant care, life expectancy, respiratory devices, and tuberculosis.
  - Alexis, Michael, 1912 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - American Association for the History of Medicine, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - American Behavioral Scientist, 1971 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - American Journal of Surgical Pathology, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - American Psychopathological Association, 1959-1970, undated (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - American Society for Eighteenth Century Studies, 1970-1971, undated (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Association for the Aid of Crippled Children, 1963 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Beaumont Medical Club, 1970-1974 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Blake, Francis, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Bulletin of the History of Medicine
    See: Series I, folder 210
  - Cancer, undated (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Ciba Symposia
    - George Rosen files
      - 1938-1940 (Box 22, Folder 11-38)
      - 1941 and undated (Box 23, Folder 39-48)
    - Beate Caspari-Rosen files
      - A (General), 1939-1949 (Box 23, Folder 49)
      - Ackernecht, Erwin H., 1944-1949 (Box 23, Folder 50)
        See also: Series I, folders 5-7
      - B (General), 1939-1949 (Box 23, Folder 51-52)
      - Barshcel, H. J., 1945-1946, undated (Box 23, Folder 53)
      - Born, Wolfgang, 1945-1956 (Box 23, Folder 54)
      - Brewer, A. D., 1939-1947 (Box 23, Folder 55)
      - C (General), 1939-1949 (Box 23, Folder 56)
      - Conn, Harold J., 1945-1947 (Box 23, Folder 57)
      - D-G (General), 1939-1949 (Box 23, Folder 58-61)
      - Gebhard, Bruno, 1945-1947 (Box 23, Folder 62)
        See also: Series I, folder 117
      - H-J (General), 1939-1949 (Box 23, Folder 63-65)
      - Jacob, H. E., 1945-1947 (Box 24, Folder 66)
      - K (General), 1939-1949 (Box 24, Folder 67)
      - Krogman, Wilton M., 1940-1945 (Box 24, Folder 68)
      - L-M (General), 1939-1949 (Box 24, Folder 69-72)
      - Montagu, M. F. Ashley, 1945-1949 (Box 24, Folder 73)
      - N-O (General), 1939-1949 (Box 24, Folder 74-75)
      - Oppenheimer, Ernst, 1939-1949 (Box 24, Folder 76-77)
        See also: Series I, folder 227
      - P-R (General), 1939-1949 (Box 24, Folder 78-79)
      - Ransom, John E., 1945-1950 (Box 24, Folder 80)
      - Robinson, Victor, 1940-1946 (Box 24, Folder 81)
      - Roder, Paul W., 1945-1949 (Box 24, Folder 82-84)
      - S (General), 1939-1949 (Box 24, Folder 85-87)
      - Spencer, Robert F., 1945-1949 (Box 24, Folder 88)
      - Stanton, Madeline, 1945-1949 (Box 24, Folder 89)
        General
        See also: Series I, folders 297-298
      - Stevenson, Isobel, 1940-1947 (Box 24, Folder 90)
      - T (General), 1939-1949 (Box 25, Folder 91)
      - Tellmadge, G. Kasten, 1945-1947 (Box 25, Folder 92)
      - Tjomsland, Anna, 1940-1949 (Box 25, Folder 93)
      - U-V (General), 1939-1949 (Box 25, Folder 94)
      - Violich, Francis, 1945-1947 (Box 25, Folder 95)
      - W (General), 1939-1949 (Box 25, Folder 96)
      - Wilson, W. J., 1940 (Box 25, Folder 97)
      - Wolff, Werner, 1944-1947 (Box 25, Folder 98)
      - Y-Z (General), 1939-1949 (Box 25, Folder 99)
      - Miscellaneous, 1939-1949 (Box 25, Folder 100)
  - Clio Medica, 1976-1977 (Box 25, Folder 101)
  - Columbia University, 1937, 1951-1959, undated (Box 25, Folder 102-103)
  - Congrès International d'Histoire de la Médecine, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 104)
  - Cushing, Harvey, undated (Box 25, Folder 105)
  - Dance frenzy, undated (Box 25, Folder 106)
  - Dictionary of American History, undated (Box 25, Folder 107)
  - Eighteenth Century Studies, 1975-1976, undated (Box 25, Folder 108)
  - Emerson, Haven, 1957-1959 (Box 25, Folder 109)
  - Freud, Sigmund [notes on early references], undated (Box 25, Folder 110)
  - Infant care, undated (Box 25, Folder 111)
  - International Academy of the History of Medicine Symposium, 1969-1973, undated (Box 25, Folder 112)
  - International Conference on Social Science and Medicine, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 113)
  - International Congress for the History of Medicine, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 114)
  - International Congress of the History of Science, 1977 (Box 25, Folder 115)
  - International Public Health Teaching Sessions, undated (Box 25, Folder 116)
  - Journal of Social Medicine, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 117)
  - Journal of the History of Medicine and Allied Sciences
    - General, 1945-1949, undated (Box 26, Folder 118-119)
      See also: Series I, folder 275
    - Annual meetings of the Board of Incorporators, 1964-1975 (Box 26, Folder 120)
  - Medical Society of the State of New York, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 121)
  - Millbank Memorial Fund, undated (Box 26, Folder 122)
  - Mountin, Joseph W., 1948 (Box 26, Folder 123)
  - National Institute of Health
    - National Conference on Preventative Medicine, 1975 (Box 26, Folder 124)
    - Oral history project
      - General, 1962-1963 (Box 26, Folder 125-128)
      - Miles, Wyndham D., 1959-1965 (Box 26, Folder 129)
      - Outline, undated (Box 26, Folder 130)
      - Proposal, 1965, undated (Box 26, Folder 131)
  - Nation's Health, 1970, undated (Box 26, Folder 132)
  - New York World's Fair, 1939 (Box 26, Folder 133)
  - Nuffield-Macy Symposium on Historical Influences on Medical Services, 1969-1971 (Box 26, Folder 134)
  - Osler Society, 1963 (Box 27, Folder 135)
  - P and S Club [medical history society], 1968 (Box 27, Folder 136)
  - Respiratory devices, Seventeenth Century, 1936, undated (Box 27, Folder 137-138)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, International Health Division, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 139)
  - Rosenau, Milton, 1965 (Box 27, Folder 140)
  - Social Science and Medicine, 1966-1977, undated (Box 27, Folder 141-145)
  - Society for Ancient Medicine, 1977, undated (Box 27, Folder 146)
  - Society for the Social History of Medicine, 1971 (Box 27, Folder 147)
  - Stimson, A. M., 1923-1931 (Box 27, Folder 148-149)
  - Streeter, Edward Clark, 1974 (Box 28, Folder 150)
  - Tuberculosis, undated (Box 28, Folder 151)
  - United States. War Department
    - General, 1945 (Box 28, Folder 152)
    - Pamphlets, 1945 (Box 28, Folder 153)
    - Technical bulletins, 1944-1947 (Box 28, Folder 154-159)
  - Urban Institute Microanalytic Simulation Model of Households, 1970 (Box 28, Folder 160)
  - Veteran's Administration, 1949-1959 (Box 28, Folder 161)
  - Winslow, Charles-Edward Amory, 1957, undated (Box 28, Folder 162)
- Writings, 1936-1977; Series IV
  Consisting of articles and books, writings are arranged alphabetically by title and cover a wide range of topics mostly related to public health and the history of medicine and science. Spanning the course of his career, most of the writings are drafts of subsequently published articles. Some folders also include correspondence, notes, and other materials documenting the process of writing and publishing. The series also includes several entries Rosen wrote on prominent individuals for biographical dictionaries. Three folders of book reviews written by Rosen and one folder of reviews of Rosen's work are filed at the end of the series.
  - George Rosen's curriculum vitae
    See: Series VI, folder 4
  - "American Medical Education: The Formative Years, 1765-1910" [book review], 1976 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - "An Analysis of Certain Sections of Marx's Kritik der Hegelschen Rechtsphilosophie ", undated (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - "Anenbrugger on Suicide", 1971 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - "Astrology and Medicine- 16th Century", undated (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - "Auscultation of the Heart", 1958, undated (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Baker, Josephine [entry written for the Dictionary of American Biography ], 1966-1968, undated (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Beaumont, William [entry written for the Dictionary of Scientific Biography ], 1968-1969 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Bernard, Claude [biographical sketch], undated (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - "Billroth in 1870", 1972 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - "Christian Fenger, Medical Immigrant", undated (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - "Contract or Lodge Practice and its Influence on Medical Attitudes to Health Insurance", undated (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - "Culture and Mental Illness: Psychic Epidemics", undated (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - "The Decline of Poverty", undated (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - "The Development of Specialization in Medicine", undated (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - "Disease, Debility, and Death: Health Hazards of Urban Life", undated (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - "Dublin Abstract", undated (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - "Early Years at the Rockefeller Center", undated (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - "The Economic and Social Thought of Paracelsus", undated (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - "Edmund A. Parkes in the Development of Hygiene", undated (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - "The Efficiency Criterion in Medical Care 1900-1920: An Early Approach to an Evaluation of Health Service", undated (Box 29, Folder 20)
  - "Enlightenment in the Medical Profession", undated (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - "Environmental Pollution", undated (Box 29, Folder 22)
  - "Eugene Sue: Physician, Dandy and Social Realist", 1970 (Box 29, Folder 23)
  - "The Evolution of Social Medicine", 1969-1971, undated (Box 29, Folder 24)
  - "Facts Do Not Speak for Themselves, or the Importance of Meaning in Medical History", undated (Box 29, Folder 25)
  - "The First Neighborhood Health Center Movement: Its Rise and Fall", undated (Box 29, Folder 26)
  - "Forms of Irrationality in the Eighteenth Century", undated (Box 29, Folder 27)
  - "Freud and Medicine in Vienna", undated (Box 29, Folder 28)
  - "From Frontier Surgeon to Industrial Hygienist: The Strange Career of George M. Kobar", undated (Box 29, Folder 29)
  - From Medical Police to Social Medicine: Essays on the History of Health Care, 1972-1974, undated (Box 29, Folder 30)
  - "Geomedizin: A Study in Political Medicine", undated (Box 30, Folder 31)
  - "Greek and Roman Attitudes Toward the Mentally Ill", undated (Box 30, Folder 32)
  - "Group Psychopathology-Psychic Epidemics", undated (Box 30, Folder 33)
  - "Hand and Occupation: A Study in the History of Occupational Medicine", undated (Box 30, Folder 34)
  - "Health and the State: The Changing Balance of Individual and Social Action", undated (Box 30, Folder 35)
  - "Health in the City: A Comparative Approach", 1974 (Box 30, Folder 36)
  - "Health in the Victorian City", undated (Box 30, Folder 37)
  - "Health Science Research in the United States", undated (Box 30, Folder 38)
  - "Historical Derivation of the Health Educator", undated (Box 30, Folder 39)
  - "Historical Evolution and Contemporary Perspectives in Primary Prevention", 1974-1975 (Box 30, Folder 40)
  - "Historical Evolution of Primary Prevention", undated (Box 30, Folder 41)
  - "The History and Future Prospects for Public Health", 1970 (Box 30, Folder 42)
  - Preface to History and Geography of the Most Important Diseases, 1964-1967 (Box 30, Folder 43)
  - "History and Health Care", [1977] (Box 30, Folder 44)
  - "History in the Study of Suicide", undated (Box 30, Folder 45)
  - History of Miners' Diseases: A Medical and Social Interpretation [notes], 1936 (Box 30, Folder 46)
  - "History of Psychiatry", undated (Box 30, Folder 47)
  - "History of Public Health in Italy" [thirteenth to fifteenth centuries], undated (Box 30, Folder 48)
  - "History of Suicide, Eighteenth and Nineteenth Centuries", undated (Box 30, Folder 49)
  - "The Idea of Social Medicine", undated (Box 30, Folder 50)
  - "Irrationality in the Eighteenth Century", undated (Box 30, Folder 51)
  - Levine, William [speech in honor of], 1968 (Box 30, Folder 52)
  - Life expectancy, undated (Box 30, Folder 53)
  - "Lorene Heister on Acupuncture: An Eighteenth Century View", undated (Box 30, Folder 54)
  - Ludwig, Carl Friedrich Wilhelm [entry in Dictionary of Scientific Biography ], 1967-1969 (Box 30, Folder 55)
  - "Madness and Society: A Social History of Mental Disorders and Other Unusual Psychological Conditions", undated (Box 30, Folder 56)
  - Madness in Society: Chapters in the Historical Sociology of Mental Illness, 1965-1977 (Box 31, Folder 57)
  - "Medical Care for Urban Workers and the Poor: Two Nineteenth Century Programs", undated (Box 31, Folder 58)
  - "Medical History and Medical Care: Historical Trends and Future Prospects in Public Health", undated (Box 31, Folder 59)
  - "Medical Philosophes and Enlightenment Physicians", undated (Box 31, Folder 60)
  - "Medical Research in the United States", 1942, undated (Box 31, Folder 61)
  - "Medicine as a Function of Society", 1969, undated (Box 31, Folder 62)
  - "Mental Disorder, Social Deviance, and Culture Pattern: Some Methodological Issues in the Historical Study of Mental Illness", 1969-1970 (Box 31, Folder 63)
  - "Michael M. Davis (1879-1971): Pioneer in Medical Care" [editorial], 1972 (Box 31, Folder 64)
  - "The Mission of the School of Public Health: Past Present, and Future", undated (Box 31, Folder 65)
  - "Modes of Feeling and Intellectual Attitudes Toward Medical Problems from the Late Fifteenth to the Seventeenth Centuries", undated (Box 31, Folder 66)
  - "Negativism: A Mode of Reaction to Innovation in Medical Care Organization", undated (Box 31, Folder 67)
  - "Nicholas Senn: Experimental Surgeon and Surgical Tourist", 1977 (Box 31, Folder 68)
  - "Nicholas Senn's Experimental Work on Cancer Transmissibility", undated (Box 31, Folder 69)
  - "Nostalgia: A 'Forgotten' Psychological Disorder", undated (Box 31, Folder 70)
  - "The Origins and Evolution of the Clinical Laboratory in the Nineteenth Century", undated (Box 31, Folder 71)
  - Park, William Haddock [entry written for the Dictionary of Scientific Biography ], 1957-1958, undated (Box 31, Folder 72)
  - "Patterns of Health Research in the United States 1900-1960", undated (Box 31, Folder 73)
  - "The Pediatrician as Historian", undated (Box 31, Folder 74)
  - "Percussion and Nostalgia", undated (Box 31, Folder 75)
  - "Population", undated (Box 31, Folder 76)
  - "Preventative Medicine in the United States 1900-1975" (Box 31, Folder 77)
  - "Psychological Conditions in a Declining Civilization", undated (Box 31, Folder 78)
  - "Psychopathology in the Social Process" [Fielding H. Garrison Lecture], [1960] (Box 31, Folder 79)
  - "Psychosomatic Medicine", undated (Box 31, Folder 80)
  - "Public Health, Then and Now" [column written for The American Journal of Public Health ]
    - " The American Journal of Public Health: Antecedents, Origin, and Evolution", undated (Box 32, Folder 81)
    - "A Backwards Glance at Noise Pollution", undated (Box 32, Folder 82)
    - "Benjamin Rush on Health and the American Revolution", undated (Box 32, Folder 83)
    - "The Case of the Consumptive Conductor, or Public Health on a Street Car: A Centennial Tribute to Alfred F. Hess, M.D.", 1975 (Box 32, Folder 84)
    - "Ellen H. Richards (1842-1911), Sanitary Chemist and Pioneer of Professional Equality for Women in Health Science", undated (Box 32, Folder 85)
    - "The Fiftieth Anniversary of the Maternal and Child Health Section: Some Remarks on its Background and Origin", 1972 (Box 32, Folder 86)
    - "John Shaw Billings and the Plan for a Sanitary Survey of the United States", undated (Box 32, Folder 87)
    - "The Richmond Meeting of the American Public Health Association", 1972 (Box 32, Folder 88)
    - "Some Recollections of Wilson G. Smillie, M.D. (1886-1971), 1972 (Box 32, Folder 89)
    - "Tenements and Typhus in New York City 1840-1875", undated (Box 32, Folder 90)
  - "The Revolt of Youth: Some Historical Comparisons", undated (Box 32, Folder 91)
  - "Revolting Youth, Past and Present", 1968-1970, undated (Box 32, Folder 92)
  - Rosenau, Milton Joseph (1869-1946) [entry for Dictionary of American Biography ], 1970 (Box 32, Folder 93)
  - "Rudolf Virchow and Neanderthal Man", undated (Box 32, Folder 94)
  - "Sir William Temple and the Use of Moxa for Gout in England", undated (Box 32, Folder 95)
  - "A Slaughter of Innocents: Some Aspects of Child Health in the Eighteenth Century", undated (Box 32, Folder 96)
  - "Social Aspects of Mental Illness", undated (Box 32, Folder 97-98)
  - "Social Change and Psychopathology in the Emotional Climate of Millennial Movements", undated (Box 32, Folder 99)
  - "Social History of Medicine", undated (Box 32, Folder 100-101)
  - "Social History of Mental Illness", 1965 (Box 32, Folder 102)
  - "Social Medicine in the United States: The Role of Non-Medical Individuals and Movements in Its Developments", undated (Box 32, Folder 103)
  - "The Social Position and Social Role of the Physician: Are They Compatible?", undated (Box 32, Folder 104)
  - "Social Science and Health in the Twentieth Century", undated (Box 32, Folder 105)
  - "Social Variables and Health in an Urban Environment: The Case of the Victorian City", undated (Box 32, Folder 106)
  - "Solomon Solis-Cohen" [introductory essay for a volume of collected papers], 1957-1959 (Box 32, Folder 107)
  - "Some Pre-suppositions of Marxian Socialism", undated (Box 32, Folder 108)
  - "Some Roots of Psychoanalysis", undated (Box 32, Folder 109)
  - "Specialization in Public Health", 1972 (Box 32, Folder 110)
  - "The Structure of the American Medical Practice 1875-1975", Circa 1976 (Box 33, Folder 111-113)
  - "Supportive Milieu in Heart and Stroke Rehabilitation: A Methodological Consideration", 1967 (Box 33, Folder 114)
  - "Tenements, Typhus, and Tuberculosis in New York City 1840-1940", undated (Box 33, Folder 115)
  - "Treating the Mentally Ill at the End of the Middle Ages", undated (Box 33, Folder 116)
  - "Urbanization, Occupation, and Disease in the United States 1870-1920: The Case of New York City", undated (Box 33, Folder 117)
  - Van Buren, William Holmes, undated (Box 33, Folder 118)
  - "The Victorian City: Images and Realities", undated (Box 33, Folder 119)
  - "Whither Specialization", undated (Box 33, Folder 120)
  - "Witchcraft-Persecution and Relation to Politics", undated (Box 33, Folder 121)
  - Book reviews, 1938-1977, undated (Box 33, Folder 122-124)
  - Reviews of Rosen's books, 1968-1969 (Box 33, Folder 125)
- Yale University Files, 1951-1977; Series V
  Arranged alphabetically, Yale University files include correspondence, memoranda, reports, minutes, syllabi, reading lists, lecture notes, and other materials documenting Rosen's tenure as a member of the Yale faculty. The files document his administrative activities within several schools and departments, his teaching, and his relationships with the administration, faculty, staff, and students of the university.
  - Appointment of George Rosen, 1968 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Brewster, Kingman, 1973 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Committee on Honors and Special Projects, 1973-1974 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Course materials [syllabi, reading lists, lecture notes], 1963-1976, undated (Box 34, Folder 4-9)
  - Department of the History of Medicine [annual reports], 1951-1953 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Department of the History of Science and Medicine, 1970-1977, undated (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Department of Public Health [also School of Epidemiology and Public Health], 1953-1974, undated (Box 35, Folder 12-17)
  - Graduate training grant, 1964, 1968 (Box 35, Folder 18)
  - Macy-Yale Symposium on History and Public Health Policy, 1970-1971 (Box 35, Folder 19)
  - Medical library, 1969-1974, undated (Box 35, Folder 20)
  - School of Medicine
    - General, 1968-1975 (Box 35, Folder 21)
    - Department of Pediatrics, 1974 (Box 35, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous, 1963-1977, undated (Box 35, Folder 23)
  - Student recommendations and evaluations, 1968-1977 (Box 36, Folder 24)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Student records are closed until January 1, 2053 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
- Personal Papers and Photographs, 1930-1977; Series VI
  The series consists of family correspondence, memorabilia, clippings, biographical material, and photographs documenting the life of George Rosen and his family. Rosen's curriculum vitae list his publications and work history. One folder of correspondence and other materials relating to his son, Peter Rosen, and daughter, Susan (Rosen) Koslow, is filed under "Children." There are a small number of photographs of the Rosens, but the majority of the photographs document the exhibit halls at the American Public Health Association annual meetings from 1928 to 1937.
  - Caspari-Rosen, Beate [biographical material], undated (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Children [Peter and Susan Rosen], 1936-1971, undated (Box 37, Folder 2)